Name: SAJJAD ALI

Address: P.e.c.h.s block 2 Liberty signal Tariq road Karachi

Contact: +923313828538 / +923133349149

Email: Sajjadalikk@live.com

**Technical Skills:** 

Java Script

PHP LARAVEL

**CODEIGNITER** 

**MERN** 

MVC

CSS3

**JSON** 

AJAX

MYSQL

**SQL LITE** 

Sublime **Crystal Report** 

**Eclipse** 

XAML / XML

ASP.Net

**JQUERY** HTML5

Web & Desktop Developments:

Win Forms Application

**SQL Server Database** 

MS Visual Studio

Adobe Dreamweaver

PHP

C#

Languages:

### CAREER OBJECTIVE:

I am a proficient developer with eight years of commercial experience in software development, specifically in web development. By using different technology stacks and putting my academic and professional experience, I have complete exposure of how software can be designed and developed and a track record of delivering quality solutions using a range of different technologies. Concentrating on C# (PHP, LARAVEL, Codeigniter, Mern, C#, Java Script, ASP.NET, MVC, Windows Desktop Applications).

I am also a keen proponent of agile methodologies and have successfully introduced agile techniques into projects which I have managed. I am seeking a challenging position as a Web developer, ideally in a project team developing large scale enterprise system.

### **EXPERIENCE:**

### Software Engineer (Genetech Solutions PVT LTD) (June 2021 to Present)

- Php, Laravel, Codelgniter, Mern, C#, Asp.net
- Design and develop software applications, support the development, Maintenance and release of software applications
- Website development, Code optimization

### Software Engineer (Duka Digital PVT LTD)

(Jan 2019 to May 2021)



genetech

- Php, Laravel, Java Script, MySQL, Json
- E-commerce store architecture design.
- Website development, Code optimization, Speed Optimization.
- Third party integration like ERP, CMS, Social Integration.
- Integration of Business requirement into real solution.

### Software Engineer (IBICO PVT LTD)

(Nov 2016 to Jan 2019)



- Php, Laravel, Codelgniter, Java Script, MySQL, Json
- Software requirement gathering, Crud Operations, Relational database modeling.
- Playing role of Scrum Team Member.
- Maintenance of projects, User friendly interface designing, Fulfill client's requirements. Data Bases:

### Visiting Faculty Member (APTECH Pvt Ltd)

(Nov 2016 to Jan 2019)



To plan, organize and implement an appropriate instructional program in a Learning environment that guides and encourages students to develop and fulfill their academic **Tools:** potential.

### Junior Software Engineer (RIZTECH SOLUTIONS)

(Oct 2014 to Nov 2106)



- Php, Laravel, Java Script, C#, Asp.net, Crystal Report, SQL Server, Desktop Application.
- Live projects and gave post live support.
- Worked on Application tuning including memory management.

### Junior Software Engineer (NETKOM PVT LTD)

(Sep 2013 to Oct 2014)



- C#, Asp.net, Crystal Report, SQL Server, Desktop Application.
- Design and develop software applications, support the development, Maintenance and release of software applications

C#, Asp.net, Crystal Report, SQL Server

### Internee Software Engineer (H.I.S.T JAMSHORO) (Feb 2013 to Sep 2013)





### **EDUCATION:**

**MS IN Computer Science** 

Muhammad Ali Jinnah University Karachi 2017 – 2019

**BS IN Computer Science** 

University of SINDH JAMSHORO 2009 – 2013

**06 Month Course from Dynamic Center** 

Web Development (PHP, Java Script, MySQL) 2012 – 2013

### **WORK EXPERIENCE PORTFOLIO:**

Web & Desktop Applications:

## **HR Management System**

(IGLOO ICE CREAM PAKISTAN)

(Asp.Net, C#, Crystal Reports, SQL Server)

HR and Payroll software allows your organization to generate pay slips and salary register, based on the attendance of the employees which is recorded through biometric time and attendance machines like Finger print scanner, Face Recognition device, and RFID card reader. While taking care of Monthly Employee Salary, Annual Leaves System, Overtime, Allowances, Loans, Advance, Bonus, Leave Encashment and Income Tax, Reports etc.

# **Student Management System**

(Millat School, Zamzama School)

(PHP Laravel, Java Script, MySQL, Reporting)

School Management System consists of tasks such as Student Registration, Student Biometric Attendance, Student Fee Management and Student Examination Management, Parents SMS Sending, Student Reports (Monthly Attendance Sheets, Exam Result Sheets and Fee Vouchers etc.) Employee Management, Employee Biometric Attendance, Employee Reports (Monthly Attendance Sheets, Employee Pay slip etc.)

### **Property Management System**

(JINNAH RESIDENCY)

(PHP, Java Script, MySQL, Reporting)

The property management software is Avail, which gives owners and managers an end-to-end platform to manage their property. It can handle tasks such as Employee Registration, Customer Registration, Property Registration, Property Sells and Purchase Management, Profit and Loss, Annual and Monthly Reports.

### **Point of Sale Software**

(CEDER COLLEGE / AL JAJAN GARMINTS)

(Windows Form, C#, Crystal Reports, SQL Server)

Point of Sale Software is a desktop application that consists of Customer, Inventory, Sale and Purchase of the company with multiple location handle with single database also connected with bar code and printer device with all related reports.

# Mineral Water Distribution System (PURE & CURE PVT LTD)

(Windows Form, C#, Crystal Reports, SQL Server)

The Water Distribution System is a web-based application that consist of task such as distributors, employee, customer, vendor management and purchase and sale of all company, profit and loss management and accounts of the company and reporting.